Ryan Stepanek

RyanStepanek@gmail.com | 918-346-1116 | Saint Michael, MN | www.datastepanek.com

DATA SCIENTIST

Data Scientist with 10+ years of experience in data analysis, data modeling, and development. Known for strong technical skills and full lifecycle experience supporting business objectives through technical expertise both locally and in the cloud. Delivers insightful data driven stories on time and under budget.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Artificial Intelligence | Machine Learning | Statistical Modeling | Data Visualization | Python | AWS Cloud | Azure Cloud | Anaconda | Pandas | Numpy | Agile

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist, Distance Digital (Minnesota)

2018 - Present

Consultant for legal, energy, and IT fields. Deep technical expertise, machine learning, data modeling, applied statistics, ETL for SQL and NoSQL databases, and EDA skills to extract value from customer data. Python, AWS, Sagemaker, Azure, TesnorFlow, Pandas, Anaconda to process data. Projects are Agile. Data dashboards via cloud, d3.js, Tableau, or Excel and PowerPoint by customer preference.

Senior Consultant, Deloitte LLP (Virginia)

2016 - 2018

Private and Public sector consultant for advanced simulation development at scale, data analysis, and data visualization in accord with state of the art practices. C# and Scala for simulation development, Unity Engine for visualition, MongoDB, custom d3.js dashboard, Excel and PowerPoint deliverables. Presented results directly to client resulting in contract renewal.

Consultant, Radiant Blue Technologies (Virginia)

2014 - 2016

Supported NRO and aerospace clients with strong data analysis, custom data processing pipelines, and data processing application development. SQL and Access databases. Python and command line tools in closed environments for ETL and EDA. Excel and PowerPoint deliverables. Agile Environment.

Data Scientist, Federal Government (Virginia)

2012 - 2014

Applied strong Natural Language Processing techniques on structured and semi-structured data to deliver unique, accurate, and timely analysis to decision makers. Python and command line tools to scrape and integrate with various API sources. ETL from SQL and NoSQL databases. Agile Environment. Deliverables presented in Excel and PowerPoint.

EDUCATION/CERTIFICATIONS

University of Tulsa - B.S. in Computer Science

University of Texas At Austin - Post Graduate Program in Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence: Business Applications

CLEARANCE

Capable of maintaining a clearance at the TS/SCI level, inquire for further details.